公元870年,英格兰
维京之王巴塞格带领他日渐衰落的军队 对抗日益强大的撒克逊抵抗军
各个独立的维京部队与撒克逊人之间的暴力冲突
使得英格兰中部地区变成极为危险的地带
在维京人对英国的控制开始动摇之际 巴塞格国王从海外召来援军
在这支援军当中最先抵达的 是他最年轻的儿子—斯坦纳王子
公元871年
“格里姆”
Yeah!
“贾库尔”
“海根”
“斯坦纳”
斯坦纳
Steinar...
你说的没错
You were right.
他们确实有脑子哩
Some of them do have brains.
比你更有脑子,你这操蛋的禽兽
More than can be said for you, you fucking animal.
这么快就能血刃敌人,真是太好了
Good that we wet our blades so quickly.
他们只是几个农民而已
They were just farmers.
那就让他们下地狱去耕田吧
Well,now they're farming in Hell.
入夜之后,我们其他的船就能上岸了
The rest of our boats will be in by nightfall.
把马匹带上来
Bring up the horses.
哈夫丹他们上岸后,就可以跟过来了
Halfdan can follow once they've landed.
父王可没多少耐心
My father's not a patient man.
格里姆、贾库尔
Grim,Jokul.
如果他是个撒克逊人,肯定会被吓一大跳
If he's a Saxon,he's gonna have a fuck of a surprise
那不是撒克逊人
- when he rides into us. - That's no Saxon.
居然只派一个人来迎接我们
So this is our welcome.
瓦里,出什么事了？
Vali,what's happened？
天兆说,如果我们早点发起进攻,就能获得胜利
The omens promised victory if we attacked early.
但是诸神没让我们如愿以偿
The Gods were against us.
你父王伤得很重,斯坦纳
Your father's badly wounded,Steinar.
带我去见他
Take me to him.
斯坦纳
Steinar.
迟到总比不到的好
Better late than never.
我说话从来都是算数的
I came when I said I would.
这就是你带来的军队？
And this is the army you brought with you？
天一亮,我们就喂他喝点稀粥
He was fed Gruel at first light.
现在都可以闻到从他胃里飘出来的洋葱味了
The onions can already be smelled through his stomach.
如果他的内脏被刺穿,我们也就无能为力了
If his guts are pierced, there's nothing more we can do.
他还能活多久？
How long？
最多一周
A week,maybe less.
听着,斯坦纳
Listen,Steinar,
我知道我们一直看对方不顺眼
I know we haven't always seen eye to eye,
不过我们毕竟是手足兄弟
but we're still brothers after all
如果我当上国王
and I want you to know that when I'm King
我一定会照顾好你的
I'll make sure you're taken care of.
天兆…欺骗了我们,斯坦纳
The omens deceived us,Steinar.
过多几个小时,一支500人的军队就要到了
An army of 500 are only hours behind me.
我们打仗的这一切理由……
All this talk of reason...
听起来就像在掩饰自己的软弱
sounds like a cover-up for weakness.
我们来到这里,因为我们别无选择
We lie here because we have no choice.
我们需要土地！
We need land!
要么占领土地
We either take it
要么面临灭亡
or our people perish.
父王,这场仗我们虽然输了
We may have lost the battle,father,
但我们仍然可以赢得这场战争
but we can still win the war.
谁来领军打仗呢？
And who'll lead them？
你？
You？
看你这身纨绔子弟的打扮,行吗？
In all your fucking finery？
我来领军,父王
I will lead our army,father.
你比他更合适
You're no more fit than he is.
也许以前合适
Once,maybe.
但在你母亲去世之后……
But after your mother left...
你变了
you changed,
违背了众神
turned your back on the Gods.
你以为了解自己的能力？
Thought you knew better,huh？
我的能力足于胜任一国之君了
I am strong enough to be King.
那就用行动来证明一下
Then prove it.
你那同父异母的弟弟
Your half brother--
我的私生子
my bastard son--
拒绝上战场
refused to enter the field of battle.
这是因为我要他发誓,等我回来再上战场的
I made him swear an oath to wait till I returned.
你也清楚那些不愿意打仗的人,会遭受什么样的惩罚
You know the punishment for those that turn their back in combat.
你来动手吧
See it's done.
我来下手,父王
I will do it,father.
别碰他,哈拉德 别碰他！
Leave him,Harald. Leave him!
给我出去！
Get out,now!
你留下,斯坦纳
Not you,Steinar.
有一个人配得上这个王位
There's a man worthy of this crown,
一个心中燃烧着烈火的人
a man with fire in his heart,
勇于挥舞诸神之锤的人
brave enough to wield the Hammer of the Gods--
我的大儿子
my firstborn.
你以前说过,谁敢提起他的名字就杀了谁
You said you'd kill anyone who mentioned his name.
时代变了
The time has passed.
谁也不知道他身在何处
Nobody knows where he is.
他失踪了好几年
He hasn't been seen for years.
去找到你哥哥
Find your brother.
找到哈坎
Find Hakan.
让他回来当国王,带领我们取得胜利
Return with a King who will lead us to victory.
这里需要我的指挥
I am needed here.
我可能一只脚踏进了鬼门关
I may be dying,
但我还是你的父王
but I'm still your King.
再顶嘴一句
Defy me again,
我就亲手把你的心挖出来
and I will cut your heart out myself.
现在发誓
Now swear
以你母亲的记忆起誓
on the memory of your mother.
我发誓
I swear.
你他妈是疯了吗
You're out of your fucking mind.
- 我发过誓了 - 誓言什么的都是狗屁,斯坦纳
- I swore an oath. - Oaths are horseshit,Steinar.
我必须遵守对他的承诺
I gave him my word. I will not break it.
哈坎现在肯定死了
Hakan is almost certain to be dead by now.
就算他没死,在他被驱逐之前,就是一个神经病了
And if he's not,he was fucking insane before he was banished;
现在肯定更加无可救药了
he'll only be more so now.
反正谁也不知道这鸟人在哪里
Anyway,who knows where the fuck he is？
- 你知道 - 这太危险了
- You do. - It's too dangerous.
危险？
Dangerous,is it？
那你肯定知道他在哪里
Then you must know where he is.
听着,假设我知道
Listen, say I do know--
其实我并不知道,但我假设我知道
which I don't, but say I did--
你肯打保票他肯回来？
what makes you think he'd come back？
那是父王的遗终愿望
It's the King's wish.
不出一个星期国王就死翘翘了
The King will be dead in a week.
你慢慢等着就是了,在他死的时候别走太远
Bide your time. Be close at hand when he dies.
等时机一到,就自立为王
And when the moment's right, you take the crown for yourself.
我们都支持你对付哈拉德
We'd all back you against Harald.
好好权衡一下吧
Think about it.
我之前说不知道哈坎在哪里,这是实话
When I said I didn't know where Hakan was, I spoke the truth.
但我知道最近一个见过他的人在哪里
But I do know how to find the last man who saw him.
不过他肯不肯告诉我们就不知道了
Whether he's capable of helping us remains to be seen.
- 要出门？ - 不关你的事,格里姆
- Going somewhere？ - It doesn't concern you,grim.
让我们过去
Let us pass.
- 休想 - 如果你知道我们要去哪的话…
- Like fuck. - You'd think differently
肯定会改变主意的
if you knew where we were going.
我们要去黑山
We're heading for the black mountains
寻找“无骨者”艾瓦尔 （注：艾瓦尔是一位维京领袖,“无骨者”是他的外号）
in search of Ivar the boneless.
那只老肥猪？
That fat fuck？
昨晚我听说他把自己的头砍了下来
Last night I heard he chopped his own head off.
我还听说他把自己变成一头熊了呢
Well,I heard he transformed himself into a bear.
你们去找那个舔鸡鸡的疯子干什么？
What do you want with that cocksucking maniac anyway？
只有他才能帮助我们找到哈坎
He's the only one who can lead us to Hakan.
路上有2天时间要穿越撒克逊领地
It's a two-day ride through saxon country,
再之后的情况也很难预料
and who knows after that？
我以为我们是胆小鬼吗？
You think we're cowards,is that it？
我听他的意思确实是这样的
It sounds like it to me.
真要是这个意思的话,就让你尝尝我操蛋斧头的滋味
'Cause if it is,you can kiss my fucking axe.
我已经听到过上天的旨意了,斯坦纳
I looked at the bones, Steinar.
天意已决,我们要结伴而行
It's already been decided-- we'll travel together.
- 天意这么说？ - 没错
- The bones said that？ - Aye.
你们两个人能走多远？
How far do you think you'll get？
带上我们,成功的机会要大一些
Take us with you-- you double your odds.
瓦里,你不能跟来
Not you,vali.
为何不行？
Well,why not？
因为你的剑就跟你的老二一样软,小子
'Cause your sword's as limp as your cock,boy.
斯坦纳,带我一起去
Steinar,take me with you.
你盯紧哈拉德,知道不？
Watch Harald,hmm？
等我回来时把他做过什么告诉我
Report to me when I get back.
太阳快落山了
The sun is sinking.
先找个地方过夜
Let's find a place to rest.
好
Yeah.
曾经有一段时间
There was a time when they did everything together--
哈坎和艾瓦尔形影不离
Hakan and Ivar.
我父亲也曾跟他们两个一同袭击过敌人
My father went raiding with them--
把敌人虐得那叫一个惨
fucking carnage.
在哈坎被驱逐之后
After Hakan was banished,
大家越来越不愿意容忍艾瓦尔的所作所为了
people were less willing to tolerate Ivar's behavior.
他知道哈坎去了何处
He knew where Hakan had gone,
于是就动身去找哈坎
so he set off after him.
为什么他外号叫“无骨者”
Why do they call him boneless？
因为谁也看不到他的老二
Because you could never see his cock,
因为他的老二总是插在
'cause it was always rammed to the hilt
某个小男孩的菊花里
up some young boy's asshole.
有人说他不会感觉到痛楚
They say he felt no pain.
这样的话小男孩的菊花也不会有痛楚
Which is more than can be said for the young boy's asshole.
我曾有几次与他并肩打仗的经历
I fought beside him a couple of times.
不管现在大家对他有什么样的看法
Whatever people think of Ivar now,
在打仗的时候都不能低估他
he was something to behold in battle.
他和哈坎都不能低估
They both were.
我父王为何驱逐哈坎？
Why did my father banish Hakan？
他受了诅咒
He was cursed.
你父王有他的理由
Your father had his reasons.
也许他做过什么都没关系了吧
Maybe it doesn't matter what he did.
要是让他当国王就有关系
It does if he's gonna be King.
斯坦纳,是我！
Steinar,it's me!
Argh!
你这样会害死你自己的
You'll get yourself killed.
我照你说的去做了
I did as you said.
我跟踪了哈拉德
I followed Harald.
你刚走不久,他也骑马外出
He rode out almost the minute you left.
他越过了撒克逊防线,去见了他们的国王
He crossed the saxon lines and spoke to their King.
他妈的贱货！
Fucking snake!
我不知道该怎么办
I didn't know what to do.
你做得对,瓦里
You did the right thing,vali.
现在趁他们没发觉你的行踪,快回去吧
You should head back now, before they notice you're gone.
不,这太危险了
No,it's too dangerous.
瓦里跟我们一起走
Vali can ride with us.
格里姆,给他一些食物
Grim,get him some food.
才不给呢 我们往回走
He can get his own food. We turn back,
把哈拉德的老二给砍了,然后给他来个透心凉
cut Harald's balls off and rip out his spine.
不,我们继续往北走
No. We continue our ride north.
斯坦纳,哈拉德已经跟撒克逊人串通在一起了
Steinar,Harald's cut a deal with the Saxons.
我们的同胞决不会支持哈拉德的
Our men would never back Harald.
想要当国王是一回事,怎么当国王又是另一回事
It's one thing to want the crown,another to take it.
在你那操蛋的兄弟
You'd rather we have us climbing mountains
把我们的女同胞出卖给一群农民的时候
on some fucking bear hunt while your cunt fuck of a brother
你还叫我们去翻山越岭？
sells our women to a bunch of farmers!
我们的女同胞比哈拉德强多了
Our women are more than a match for Harald.
格里姆
Grim,
没人强迫你来
nobody forced you to come.
也没人强迫你留下
Nobody's forcing you to stay.
我知道你在为自己的信仰而战
Oh,I know you struggle with your beliefs,
无视了众神的旨意……
that you deny the Gods and the significance of signs...
不过瓦里一个人星夜兼程来到这里
But a lone rider arriving under a full Moon？
对于我们所有人来说,恐怕都是一个凶兆吧？
Even you can't deny what a bad omen that is for all of us.
他虽然年轻,但天性善良
He's young. He's got good instincts.
他会为我们带来生命危险的
He brings death with him.
我不会为了你的迷信
I'm not about to turn against him
抛弃他的
for the sake of your superstitions.
如果一个人不相信天兆
If a man doesn't believe in omens,
那他怎么知道自己该相信什么？
then how can he know what he believes in？
他可以相信自己
He can believe in himself.
不要扔了！
No!
我们应该继续赶路
We should ride on.
贱货！
You bitch!
说的对
You're right.
住手！
Stop!
住手
Stop.
- 放了她 - 去你的,异教徒
- Let her go. - Fuck you,heathen.
Argh!
- 你没事吧？ - 他妈的疯婆娘
- You all right？ - Crazy fucking bitch.
走吧
Let's go.
马儿走不动了
The horses won't make it much further.
我们步行吧
Then we continue on foot.
瓦里,你在这里守着马匹,等我们回来
Vali,you wait with the horses till we return.
不要生火
Don't light a fire.
火会引来食人魔
Fires attract cave trolls.
别担心
Don't worry.
它们只吃处女
They only eat virgins.
只要是饿了它们什么都会吃
They'll eat anything if they're hungry enough.
提到“食人魔”,你老妹怎么样了呢？
Speaking of cave trolls,how is your sister？
去你丫的,格里姆
Fuck you,grim.
她确实饿了什么都会吃
She certainly did.
我老二每次拉尿都会隐隐作痛
Still hurts when I piss.
明天一早我们就会回来
We'll be back by first light.
斯坦纳
Steinar.
谢谢
Thanks.
我们是兄弟,客气什么
We're brothers.
什么来的？
What was that？
也许我们该等到天黑再行动
Perhaps we should wait till nightfall.
一些动物害怕月光
Some creatures fear the Moon.
晚上会安全一点
It would be safer.
艾瓦尔,是我--海根·格雷提森
Ivar,it's me-- hagen grettison.
我是巴塞格的儿子斯坦纳
My name is Steinar,son of bagsecg.
你他妈来这干什么呢,王子殿下？
What the fuck are you doing here,prince？
你想跟我过两招？
You wanna fuck with me？
尽管挣扎啊 尽管挣扎啊
I'll bet you do. I'll bet you do.
艾瓦尔,国王快死了
Ivar,the King is dying.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
人生自古谁无死呢
Everyone dies some time.
你说对不对,王子殿下？
How about you,prince？
想不想今天就死？
Do you want to die today？
我们在找新的国王--
We seek the new King--
哈坎
Hakan.
这么说你在找你哥哥？
So you're looking for your brother？
知道他在哪吗？
Know where he is？
我为什么要告诉你？
Why the Hell would I tell you？
出于对我的尊重吧
Out of respect.
尊重不是与生俱来的,小王子
Respect is not a birthright,little prince.
你想要别人尊重,得自己去争取
You want someone's respect, you've got to earn it.
你想要我的尊重？
You want to earn my respect？
你得表现得比你这副模样更强一点才行
You'd better be stronger than you look.
- 肯定有其他办法的 - 他没有痛感
- There has to be another way. - He feels no pain.
只能让他自愿告诉我们
The only way he'll tell us is through choice.
3杯酒,代表3次机会
Three cups for your three chances.
你赢了,我就什么都告诉你
You win-- I'll tell you everything you want.
我赢了-- 你就喝
I win-- you drink.
3杯全喝掉的话,你就输了
You drink all three-- you lose
然后今晚你就任由我玩弄了
and you're mine for the night, to do with as I see fit.
Ah.
手背碰到桌子就算输
First to fold or break.
开始！
Begin!
加油,斯坦纳
Come on,Steinar.
- 加油,斯坦纳 - 肩膀一起用力
- Come on,Steinar. - Put your shoulder into it.
- 搞定他,斯坦纳 - 加油
- Take him,Steinar. - Come on,Steinar.
- 加油 - 搞定他
- Come on. - Take him.
喝了,小王子
Drink up,little prince.
喝了之后你的老二才会长毛
That'll put hairs on your ball sack.
你应该有办法的吧
Tell me you have a plan.
趁我们的老二都还硬,再来一发怎么样？
Shall we go again while our cocks are still hard？
手背碰到桌子就算输
First to fold or break.
- 开始 - 加油
- Begin. - Come on.
- 肩膀用力啊 - 加油
- Put your shoulder into it. - Come on.
加油！
Come on! Come on.
加油,斯坦纳
Come on,Steinar.
我操
- Oh,fuck! - Fuck.
连下2盘
Two down,
还剩一杯
one to go.
机会渺茫咯,王子殿下
What chance now,Princess,hmm？
贾库了,你的腰带
Jokul,your belt.
快给我你的腰带
Give me your belt,quick.
腰带
Your belt.
好,斯坦纳 “圣蛇”会保佑你
Good,Steinar. The serpent will protect you.
有众神的支持,你不能输,知道吗？
With the Gods on your side, you can't lose. Hmm？
好
Yeah.
无论如何我们都支持你,你知道的
We've got your back. You know that.
但现在唯一能阻止他的是做掉他
But the only way we'll stop him is if we kill him.
Ahh.
我很想好好玩弄你的菊花呢,王子殿下
I am looking forward to making a woman out of you,Princess.
哦,不要这么苦逼的表情嘛
Oh,don't look so sad.
你可能会觉得很爽的哦
You might even enjoy it.
手背碰到桌子就算输
First to fold or break.
开始
Begin.
加油,斯坦纳,用力！
Come on,Steinar,push!
加油,把他压下去
Come on,break his fucking wrist.
加油！加油！
Come on! Come on!
Oh. Oh. Argh!
Ooh ooh.
Ooh.
你之前说你叫什么名字来着？
What did you say your name was？
斯坦纳
Steinar.
你真是个混蛋,斯坦纳
You're an asshole,Steinar.
不过我喜欢
I like assholes.
我不是自愿离开的
I didn't leave out of choice.
我成为一个persona non grata （意为“不受欢迎之人”）
I became persona non grata.
这是拉丁语,哈坎教我的
That's latin. Hakan taught me that.
他是一个伟人
He's a prodigious man,a great man really.
为什么你现没和他在一起？
How come you're not with him now？
打仗的时候,人们因为你杀人而喜欢你
You kill people in battle-- they love you for it.
与几个小男孩一起“犯错误”……
Make a mistake with a couple of boys--
他们就认为你是变态
they treat you like a leper.
你还好吗,王子殿下
You all right there,Princess.
感觉满脑子嗡嗡作响？
Feeling the 'shrooms-s-s-s？
啊,哈坎整个人完全变了
Ah,Hakan's not the man he was.
变的不像是个人了
Not a man at all really.
你们看,我们就这么浑浑噩噩的
You see,we're-- we're all this,
但他……
but he--
高高在上的
he's all that up there,
注视着我们
all around us.
你以为他会心甘情愿地跟你去
Do you think he is just gonna pack up and follow you,
统治那些驱逐他的人们？
rule the people that banished him？
他凭什么要跟你说话、跟你见面？
Why would he even speak to you,look at you？
他已经知道你会来的
He already knows you're coming.
那他应该不会介意……
Then he won't mind...
你把他的下落告诉我
if you tell us where he is.
如果我告诉你,就得杀你灭口
But if I do that,you're going to die.
呃,人生自由谁无死
Well,everybody has to die.
Oh.
不管了,王子殿下
Oh,fuck it,Princess,
单单告诉你太没劲了
i'll do better than tell you where he is.
我带你们去见他
I'll take you there myself.
有何不可啊？
Why the Hell not？
你说他妈的对不对？
Why the fucking Hell not,hmm？
Ah.
它可以帮你看穿乌云,找到阳光
Helps you see through the clouds, to find the sun.
- 这是魔法吗？ - 没有魔法这种东西。
- Is it magic？ - No such thing as magic.
上面刻有字呢
It's inscribed.？
对。你怎么会认字的？
Yeah. Who taught you to read？
我曾在修道院里呆过
I was at a monastery.
那里的人教了我……
They taught me...
很多事情
many things.
这个送给你吧
Here,here you go. Have this.
可以吹的
You blow it.
艾瓦尔说从这里2天路程之外
Boneless says there's a runestone
在西部山脉的山脚下
two days from here at the edge of a forest
一座森林边缘处有一个符文石
at the foot of the western mountains.
他会带我们找到这块石头,然后我们就可以按照符文找到哈坎
Says he'll take us there and the runes will lead us to Hakan.
- 你相信他？ - 为什么不？
- And you trust him？ - Why not？
- 他是个疯子啊 -  对,他确实是疯子
- Because he's a maniac. - Oh yeah,that he is.
但他现在很乐意帮助我们呢
But he's our maniac now.
瓦里！
Vali!
先是太阳出现血色
First the sun,
现在连大地也被鲜血染红了
and now the ashes painted red.
瓦里！
Vali!
- 斯坦纳 - 瓦里
- Steinar. - Vali.
- 斯坦纳 - 你没事吧？
- Steinar. - Are you all right？
出什么事了？ 到底出什么事了？
What happened here？ What happened？
有人来了
Men came.
昨天晚上
Last night.
我听到有人说话,以为是你们
I heard voices. I thought it was you.
为什么你身上一点伤也没有？
How come there's not a scratch on you？
这是另一个天兆
It's another omen.
我们应该回去,众神现在与我们为敌
We should turn back. The Gods are against us.
这是谁干的？盗贼？
Who did this？ Thieves？
要是盗贼会把马全部牵走的
Thieves would have taken all the horses.
有人想妨碍你们
Someone trying to fuck with you.
谁想来妨碍我们的？出来啊
You wanna fuck with us？ Come on.
来呀！
Come on!
艾瓦尔,走路去的话要多长时间？
Ivar,how long will it take us to get there on foot？
那要看你的心意坚决到什么程度了
Depends how determined you are.
非常坚决
Determined.
我们应该等待月亮来指引我们
We should wait for the Moon to guide us.
你他妈别老提月亮了
Shut your mouth about the fucking Moon.
听
Listen.
瓦里,你们两个在这里等着
Vali,you two,wait here.
管他的,要打就打吧！
Fuck this. Let's fight!
格里姆！
Grim!
Argh!
操
Fuck.
斯坦纳！
Steinar!
Arghh!
我们应该去追击他们,把他们全干掉
We should go after them,finish them off.
还是继续走吧
We move on.
我不是叫你等着的吗
I told you to wait.
我不是小孩子了
I'm not a child,Steinar.
去把那女孩带过来
Go and get the girl.
快
Now.
斯坦纳！
Steinar!
他死得很英勇
He died a good death,
战斗到最后一刻
with his axe in his hand.
瓦尔哈拉会收留他的
Valhalla won't know what hit them.
到小山上可以看得更清楚一点
There's a clear view on the hill.
瓦里,到那上面去
Vali,get up there,
看到有情况就喊一下
shout if you see anything.
艾瓦尔怎么样了？
How's Ivar？
剩下半条命了
Nearly done.
我们得尽快上路
We need to move on as soon as we can.
必须找到哈坎
We have to reach Hakan.
袭击我们的不是普通的撒克逊人
They were no ordinary Saxons.
他们的装备更精良
They were too well armed,
更加训练有素
too well trained.
遇到他们并非偶然
They didn't just run into us.
难道有人在追杀我们？
You think we're being hunted？
如果哈拉德与他们的国王结盟了
If Harald made an alliance with their King,
那么把我除掉肯定是他们谈好的条件之一
then getting rid of me would be part of the deal.
但是他们得先知道你的行踪才行啊
They'd need to know where to look for you.
也许有人在为他们通风报信
Maybe someone's helping them.
你可别跟我来月亮和天兆之类的那一套鬼话
Don't tell me you believe in all that crap about Moons and omens.
我只相信自己亲眼所见的事实
I believe what I see with my own eyes.
好
Right.
看这个
Here.
是瓦里掉的
Vali dropped it.
看看上面的图案
Look at the markings.
这是一枚撒克逊银币
It's a saxon coin.
你认为瓦里在为我们的敌人卖命？
You think vali is a servant of our enemies？
如果他听命于与撒克逊人串通的哈拉德,那就没错了
If he serves Harald,who himself serves the Saxons,it amounts to the same thing.
凭一块银币就能判断？ 他可是我兄弟啊
All from a piece of silver？ He's my brother.
只是同父异母的而已,他母亲是个撒克逊人
Half brother. His mother's a Saxon.
- 你这是什么屁话 - 你不是说过自己很讲道理还讲逻辑
- Listen to yourself. - You say you believe in reason and logic.
当逻辑摆在你面前时又视而不见
When it's presented to you, you turn your back on it.
我哪里不讲道理和逻辑了？
In what way do my actions betray a lack of reason？
当你应该战斗时却逃跑
You run when you should fight.
当你应该去领导自己的同胞之时
You set off on this meaningless quest
却在进行这个毫无意义的跑腿差事
when you should be leading your people.
当你应该与最亲密的老朋友 站在同一阵线的时候
And then you side with a bastard traitor
却又在袒护这个随时随地
who would stick a knife in your back,
会朝你背上捅一刀的杂种叛徒
rather than your oldest friend.
那你想我怎么样？
What would you have me do,huh？
嗯？杀了他？
Hmm？ Kill him？
最好如此
Better if you did.
他只是个孩子 好好想想吧
He's a child. Think about that.
想想你那2个女儿
Think about your two daughters.
非常时期需要非常手段,斯坦纳
Dark times call for dark deeds,Steinar.
你错了,海根
You're wrong,hagen.
非常时期更需要正当之举
They call for light.
斯坦纳！
Steinar!
快
Come on.
快点！
Hurry up!
- 我们打不过他们的！ - 我来挡一下他们！
- We can't outrun them! - I'll slow them down!
该死
Damn.
你叫什么来着？
What do they call you？
拜托,你肯定有名字的吧
Come on,you must have a name.
自个儿撸去吧
Go fuck yourself.
太令人失望了
That's disappointing.
还以为当王子的都有些料儿的呢
I had expected more from a prince.
不管你与我兄弟达成什么交易
Whatever deal you struck with my brother,
都不会长久的
it won't last.
兄弟
Brother.
眼下的形势
Right now
我们可以互相帮助
we're in a position where we can help each other.
我可以确保
I could help make sure
你当上你那些同胞的国王
you become King of your people.
我们之间可以成立一个真正的联盟
We could forge a real alliance
这个联盟可以持续好几代人
that could last generations.
要我们生活在十字架的阴影之下？
- Under the shadow of the cross？ - Under the protection
生活在一个仁慈的国王
of a benevolent King and a church
和一个鼓励教育和学习的教会保护之下
that would encourage education and learning.
哦,我看得出教育和学习的好处
Well,I can see the benefits in education and learning,
但是当你提到你们的上帝的时候
but when you start talking about your God,
似乎并没有什么理性可言,对吧？
reason doesn't really come into it,does it？
好好考虑一下吧
Think about it.
拜托,就喝一口
Come on,just a sip.
割断绳子
Cut my ropes.
小心！
Watch out!
再插他一刀
Stab him again.
再插
And again.
And again. And again.
你们没事吧？
You all right？
他怎么样？
What about him？
他不喜欢被绑起来
Didn't like being tied up.
把一个卫兵的耳朵咬了下来
Took one of the guard's ears off.
瓦里在哪？
Where's vali？
他跟他们一起去见圣人了
He went with them to meet their holy men
还要在白色基督像面前跪拜
and bow down before the white Christ.
别让他死了
Keep him alive.
得叫他告诉我们去哪里找哈坎
We need him to tell us where we're going.
- 我要带瓦里一起走 - 听着,斯坦纳
- I'm not leaving without vali. - Look,Steinar.
他否认了众神的存在
He denied the existence of the Gods.
他乞求改变信仰
He begged to be converted.
不要管他了
Let the boy go.
你们竟敢闯入上帝的圣地？
You dare break the sanctity of the House of God？
别跟我说什么信仰,
You talk of reason. When it comes down to it,
你就跟其他人一样迷信
you're just as superstitious as the rest of them.
现在放下你们的武器
Now lay down your weapons
放了那个小伙子
and let the boy go.
我们会追你到天涯海角
Oh,we will hunt you down
然后像杀畜生一样杀了你
and kill you like the godless animals you are.
你们跑这大老远来
You go to such lengths
建造这些教堂
to build these churches,
用它们来把恐惧
making sure they strike terror
植入到来这里的人心中
into the hearts of all who come near.
可它们只不过是一个带有门的屋子
It's just a room with a door...
跟监狱没有区别
no different to a prison.
斯坦纳！
Steinar!
把他们关到里面去！
Secure them inside!
进去！
Get in!
知道怎么找到哈坎了吗？
Do we have what we need to find Hakan？
你遵守了承诺
You were true to your word.
让他记住我,王子殿下
Remember me to him,prince.
当你见到他时
When you see him,
他的双眼可以看穿灵魂
his eyes pierce the soul.
他知道
He knows
你的真正本性,懂吗？
who you truly are,hmm？
就像一个神明……
Like a God...
看着凡人一样
sees men.
你也相信众神的吧？
You believe in the Gods,don't you,hmm？
你相信……
You believe in...
瓦尔哈拉？
Valhalla？
对
Yeah.
Oh.
瓦尔哈拉,我来了
Valhalla,I'm coming.
Shh shh.
这是谁的？
Whose was this？
- 我母亲的 - 她去哪了？
- It belonged to my mother. - What happened to her？
她被黑暗所吞噬
She was swallowed up into the darkness.
就像万事万物一样
Like everything else.
- 你们杀完了没有？ - 还有那男孩
- Are you finished？ - The boy.
- 他怎么了？ - 他自愿跟随敌人
- What about him？ - He went willingly,
还准备接受基督教
prepared to accept the white Christ.
你这样会惹来杀身之祸的
It was that or death.
你不肯让步的话,我们也不会
You didn't yield and neither did we.
我现在决不让步
And I won't now.
瓦里只会给我们带来厄运
Vali has brought us nothing but bad luck.
如果我们把他献祭给众神
If we offer him up as a sacrifice,
在接下来的时间里众神肯定会眷顾我们的
the Gods will look over us for the rest of our journey.
为了保护我们同胞的未来,这是值得的
It's worth it to safeguard the future of our people.
只要有你这种想法的人,我们的同胞就没有未来
So long as there's men who think like you,our people have no future.
他是个叛徒和懦夫,他应该去死
He's a traitor and a coward. And he deserves to die.
- 让开,斯坦纳 - 别逼我
- Step aside,Steinar. - Don't make me do this.
那你就让我别无选择
Then you leave me no choice.
让开！
Yield!
不！
No!
教堂里的人怎么办？
What about the people in the church？
等一下
Wait.
不能碰它
No,we shouldn't touch it.
我跟你说,这可不单是一根棍子插着一个人头
I'm telling you,this isn't just somebody's head on a stick.
这是个标志
This is a sign.
表示我们不能进去
This is telling us to stay the fuck away.
这是什么？
Well,what is it？
这是个符文石
It's a runestone.
就是艾瓦尔要带我们找的
This is what Ivar was leading us to.
这可不妙啊,斯坦纳
This isn't good,Steinar,I'm telling you.
要找到哈坎,就得先找到这个
To find Hakan,we had to find this first.
上面写着什么？
What does it say？
写的不是如何找到哈坎
This isn't telling us how to find Hakan.
而是个警告
It's a warning,
如果我们找了就会有可怕的后果
saying what will happen if we try.
这是啥意思？
Well,what does it mean？
意思是我们离哈坎很近了
It means we're close,
仅此而已
nothing more,nothing less.
我不能进去,斯坦纳
I can't go in there,Steinar.
就是不行
I just can't.
- 没啥好怕的,贾库尔 - 我知道这些事情
- Nothing to fear,Jokul. - I know these things.
如果我走进森林,我就死定了
If I step foot in that forest,I'm dead.
你不进也会死
You'll be dead if you don't.
贾库尔
Jokul.
阿格尼斯！
Agnes!
你没有死……
You're not dead...
还没有
Not yet anyway.
你想知道为何还没死吗？
You want to know why you're not dead？
嗯？
Huh？
Huh？ Huh？
因为这是他的决定
Because he chose it.
他决定谁生谁死
He decides who lives,who dies.
你是谁？
Who are you,huh？
我是……
I am
史学家乌尔里克
Ulric the chronicler...
大王的仆人
a humble servant of the great master.
那好吧,乌尔里克
Well,Ulric,
麻烦你去告诉你们大王
if you wouldn't mind telling the great master
说他弟弟来找他了
that his brother's here to see him.
他没有弟弟
He has no brother,
没有父亲,没有母亲
no father,no mother.
不过我会向他转告的
I'll tell him what you said though.
他听了也许会很开心
It might amuse him.
瓦里？
Vali？
瓦里,放我下来
Vali,untie me.
瓦里,阿格尼斯在哪里？
Vali,where's Agnes？
贾库尔呢？
Where's Jokul？
瓦里？
Vali？
你真是大老远跑到这里来啊,斯坦纳
You're a long way from home,Steinar.
他也是走了很远才到这里的
So is he.
这里是他的家
This is his home.
我们的父王要死了
Our father's dying.
当你想到家的时候
What do you see...
你看到了什么？
when you think of home？
看到了……
I think of the...
蓝天
the blue of the sky,
葱郁的森林
the green of the forest.
小松林
The smell of the pine trees.
我什么也看不见
I see nothing.
什么也没有……
Nothing...
只有黑暗
but darkness.
你为什么……
Why have you
来这里？
come here？
是我们的父王派我来的
Our father sent me.
他派我来带你回去
He sent me to bring you back...
当国王
to lead your people as King.
你不知道自己将要面对什么
You don't know what you ask,
但你很快就知道了
but you will.
开始盛宴吧！
Let the feast begin!
朋友们
Friends,
这是一个重要的日子
- this is a momentous day. - Yeah!
这是一个重要的时刻
This is a truly momentous occasion.
开始疯狂庆祝吧！
Commence the festivities!
跟我一起来的人怎么样了？
The people I arrived with-- what happened to them？
喂
Hey,
哈坎出走的时候,你多大？
how old were you when Hakan left？
10岁……11岁
10,11.
难道你从来没想过他为何出走？
Were you never curious as to why？
我一直爱着你
I always loved you.
从来不想我们分开
I never wanted us to be separated.
所有当母亲的都不愿意骨肉分离
No mother would ever wish for such a thing.
但现在要改变了
But that's all going to change now.
现在是时候让全世界
Now is the time for the world
拜倒在他的神威之下
to bow down before his might.
哈坎！哈坎！哈坎！
Hakan! Hakan! Hakan!
所有人都跪在他面前
All men will bow down before him.
哈坎！哈坎！哈坎！
Hakan! Hakan! Hakan!
哈坎！哈坎！ 哈坎！哈坎！
Hakan! Hakan! Hakan! Hakan!
跪在国王面前！
Bow down before the King!
哈坎！哈坎！ 哈坎！哈坎！
Hakan! Hakan! Hakan! Hakan!
跪下,跪在你的国王面前
Bow before him. Kneel before your King.
你敢藐视他？
Do you deny him？
没错
I deny him.
你胆敢怀疑你的国王
You dare question your King.
你胆敢怀疑你的神明
You dare question your God.
现在你的怀疑
Now your questions will be answered
将会通过他的神威……
through his immortality...
还有你的灭亡……来获得解答
...and your destruction.
斯坦纳
Steinar.
哈坎在哪？
Well,where's Hakan？
你派他去找他哥哥
He was sent to find his brother
他却带着哥哥的人头回来
and he returns with his head in a bag.
我派他去寻找王者
He was sent to find the King.
看来他已经找到了
Looks like he found one.
我们营地里有多少人？
How many people do we have in camp？
600到650个
600,650.
天亮前我们还能召集多少？
How many more could we muster by the morning？
几百个
A few hundred more.
我们离撒克逊军队有多远？
And how far away is the saxon army？
骑马一天不到
No more than a day's ride.
好
Good.
天一亮我们就出发
We leave at first light.
张开嘴
Open your mouth.
吞下去！
Swallow it!